Previously on "Transformers Prime"...
在上一集里
No, don't move or talk. Just power down.
不 别动也别说话 保存力量
A new power dominates your world.
一个新政权统治了你们的世界
Any further attempts to attack me
任何针对我的进一步挑衅行为
will be met with even greater force!
我都会加倍奉还！
Miko,
神子！
no cellphone! You know the rules!
不许用手机 你知道规矩的！
One text couldn't hurt, could it?
一条短信应该不会有事吧？
I realize Optimus sent us all to different locations to make us harder for the 'Cons to find,
我明白擎天柱为避免虎子抓到我们 将我们分别传送到不同地点
but if we don't know where in the world anyone else went, how are we gonna find them?
但如果我们不知道其他人的位置 该怎么找到他们呢？！
Tell me the location of your compatriots,
告诉我你同伙的藏身之地
no matter what it takes or how long.
用什么手段 花多长时间
Assemble a team and disembark for Cybertron immediately.
集结一支队伍 立刻飞往塞博特恩
He lives?
他还…活着！
Shockwave!
震荡波！
Lord Megatron.
威震天陛下
This is quite an unexpected turn.
这可真是一份大大的意外之喜
I thought you'd perished on Cybertron.
我以为你已经在塞博特恩阵亡了
Yes, as... as did we all.
是啊 是啊 我们都这么以为…
Reports of my demise were greatly premature.
如此轻易地宣告我的死亡 过于草率了
A pair of Autobots infiltrated my facility on Cybertron,
两个汽车人潜入了我在塞博特恩上的实验室
sabotaging my space bridge.
破坏了我的太空桥
I gave chase but failed to accurately calculate the outcome.
我尝试进行追击 但却徒劳无功
I awoke in the rubble, blinded.
我在一片废墟之中醒来 完全失明
It soon became clear that I was marooned on our dead planet
我很快意识到 我所在的星球已被遗弃
with no means of communication.
没有留下任何通信渠道
In time, I repaired my wounds and resumed my experiments.
我花费时日修复了自身的伤口 并重新投身于我的实验之中
The solitude enabled me to make tremendous advances in my research.
与世隔绝的我心无旁骛 于是我的研究突飞猛进
Until one day,
直到有一天
my instruments detected a massive surge of unidentifiable energy.
我的系统检测到不明能量大规模激增…
I traveled to investigate its origin at the edge of the Sea of Rust,
于是我前往锈海边缘调查其源头
where I encountered your salvage team
在那里我与您的搜索队不期而遇
and the smoldering wreckage of the Omega Lock.
并发现了终极之锁的残片
But this was not the search party I had anticipated so long ago.
但是这个搜索队并不是为我而来
Leaving one unanswered question.
所以我有一个问题亟需解答：
Why was I left for scrap, abandoned?
为什么将我留下自生自灭 为什么将我遗弃
Why?
为什么？
The... the... the explosion, it...
那…那场大爆炸…
it collapsed the power-core chamber.
使核心能量室崩塌了
The last thing anyone witnessed was you charging into the space-bridge portal.
我们只目睹你冲进太空桥入口
No one saw you come back out!
但没人看见你出来！
I find your reply to be... logical.
我判定 你的回答…符合逻辑
But you will be pleased to know that I avenged your seeming demise by
不过有件事一定会让你非常高兴
personally terminating the Autobot Cliffjumper.
我亲手解决了汽车人飞过山！
Careful, Starscream. You may dislocate a landing gear patting yourself on the back.
杀个小角色也值得炫耀 红蜘蛛 小心风大闪了舌头
As Megatron's First Lieutenant,
作为威震天的首席副官
allow me to welcome you back to the winning team.
请允许我欢迎你回归胜利之师
And allow me to clarify the new chain of command.
那么也请允许我来颁布新的指挥体系
While Starscream will retain authority over military operations,
在红蜘蛛保持军事行动指挥权的同时
Shockwave will be my First Lieutenant in charge of all scientific endeavors.
任命震荡波为我的首席副官 掌管一切科学研究事宜
Affirmative.
正是如此
Completely logical, my liege.
毫无逻辑性可言 我的君王
Hey, you hungry?
嘿 你饿了吗？
There's a town up ahead.
前面有个小镇
I'd better not. I'm running low on cash.
还是算了吧 我的钱包已经瘪了
At least you don't have to buy gasoline.
至少你不用买汽油
I'm pulling over anyway. Need to stretch my legs.
但我还是要停一下 得活动下筋骨…
Oh, yeah.
啊 舒坦！
Arcee... team Prime is scattered to the winds.
阿尔茜 领袖卫队已经四分五裂了
For all we know, you and I could be the only ones left.
从目前的情况看 你和我可能是仅有的幸存者
I don't believe that, Jack, and I know you don't either.
我不这么认为 杰克 而且我知道你也一样
Maybe not.
也许吧
But the Decepticons outnumber us 100 to 1.
但是敌我力量相差如此悬殊
Aren't there any more Autobots out there who could help?
难道就没有其他汽车人能助我们一臂之力吗？
The War For Cybertron took a heavy toll.
塞博特恩之战伤亡惨重
But there were others who escaped in the ark.
但当时确实有人乘方舟逃了出去
So, where are they?
那么…他们在哪儿？
Scattered to the winds.
流落四方…
So, let's focus on getting back to Jasper
所以我们还是把精力集中在赶回贾斯帕
and getting team Prime back together.
重聚领袖卫队上吧
Nada, Bee.
没有新发现 小蜂
Just the same old rubber masks and bad C.G.
还是那些早就看过的合成图片
But the usualconspiracy websites might be our only chance to...
网站也许是我们找到其他人的唯一途径了…
Whoa! I found something!
看！我找到了！
It's Ratchet!
是救护车！
Shockwave's toadying is so transparent.
震荡波明显是在向我示威
Megatron's respect is earned by deeds, not words.
威震天只重视实干家 而非信口开河之徒
Useless, useless, useless.
没用！没用！没用！
Billions of cameras in the hands of those miserable humans.
那些讨厌的人类手上有数十亿台照相机
One of them is bound to catch an Autobot eventually.
总会有人拍到汽车人的…
Well, well, well.
瞧啊 瞧啊
What have we here?
这是谁呢？
Lord Megatron, I have found something of great interest!
威震天陛下 我找到了点您一定会感兴趣的东西！
The photo was taken yesterday
这张照片是昨天拍的
in a junkyard outside Woodland Park.
在森林公园外的废车场
I'd better scrub Ratchet and replace him with...
我得删去救护车 再替换上…
An Autobot!
一个汽车人！
Wait, what?
等等 什么？
It was just here! Surely, one of you saw it.
他刚才还在上面的！你们肯定有人看见了！
Starscream...
红蜘蛛
you would do well to take a cue from Soundwave on occasion
有时候你要向声波好好学学
and keep things to yourself!
别总是一惊一乍的
Vow of silence... such a cop-out.
给我安静点 这该死的图片
Lord Megatron,
威震天陛下
surely our Autobot prisoner is a better source of information than this primitive data net.
比起这个落后的数据网络 我们的汽车人俘虏无疑是更好的消息来源
I will have you know, Shockwave, that I have been grinding Wheeljack down for days.
提醒你一下 震荡波
If he knew anything, he would've spilled it by now.
如果他真知道些什么 早就全盘托出了
Again, some prove to be better at holding their tongues than others.
的确 有些人确实比其他人更能管住自己的嘴
Perhaps you would have better results if instead of a club you used a scalpel.
如果你放弃低劣的肉体折磨 而使用一些尖端的科技 效果可能会更好
I recommend a cortical psychic patch.
我推荐我的大脑神经接入器
I don't think he's coming.
我觉得他不会来了
Don't worry, Miko...
别担心 神子
every Wrecker knows the protocol.
每个雷霆救援队员都熟知紧急方案
Jackie will show. If he's still kicking.
只要他还活着 老千就一定会出现…
Do your worst, Doc.
拿出你的看家本领吧 医生
I'm a Wrecker. I can take it.
我是名雷霆救援队员 我扛得住
Trust me... you, in fact, cannot.
相信我 事实上 你不能
The patch failed to yield any new information on the whereabouts of the Autobots.
接入器没能取得任何关于汽车人行踪的新信息
Um... I see...
嗯…我知道了…
Ah, then it would seem that Wheeljack has outlived his usefulness.
这么看来 千斤顶已经没有利用价值了
With your permission, Lord Megatron,
如果您允许 威震天陛下
I will see to his immediate termination.
我立刻去把他解决掉…
Wake up, Wrecker.
醒醒 雷霆救援队小子
Time to smelt.
该洗热水澡了！
Commander Starscream wanted you conscious
红蜘蛛指挥官想让你清醒过来
so you'd know precisely who ordered your execution.
这样你就能明白是谁送你上路
Where is Screamy?
小红他人呢？
Doesn't have the bearings to do this himself?
他不敢亲自动手？
Jump.
跳下去！
Hey, are you a flier?
嘿 你会飞吧？
Okay, I'll jump.
好吧 我跳就是了
Thought so!
果然能飞！
Thanks for the ride.
谢谢你捎我一程
This is how you handle things?!
你就是这么办事的？
Wheeljack is not the first prisoner to escape Starscream's care.
千斤顶不是第一个从红蜘蛛手上逃走的俘虏了
Actually, master,
实际上 主人
I allowed Wheeljack to escape.
是我故意让千斤顶逃走的
You what?!
你说什么？！
But the Autobot's every move,
但是那个汽车人的一举一动
his every word, will be monitored.
一言一语都会在我们的监视之下…
Thanks to a simple tracking device implanted while the prisoner was still unconscious,
因为我在囚犯昏迷不醒时 给他植入了一枚简易跟踪器
following the failed cortical psychic patch.
当然 是在某人的大脑神经接入器失败后实施的
Now all we have to do is wait, watch, and listen.
接下来 我们只需要等一等 看一看 听一听
When the Wrecker reunites with the other Autobots,
一旦他与其他汽车人会合
my armada will strike.
我的大军就会将他们一网打尽…
He's got to be here.
他应该就在这儿！
Ratchet! Ratchet, it's me, Raf!
救护车！救护车 是我 拉夫
Uh, Ratchet?
嗯…救护车？
Go away!
走开
You're interrupting my power down.
你们打扰到我的休息了！
Come on, Ratchet, we need your help to find the others.
别闹了 救护车 我们需要你的帮助来找到其他人
We can't stop Megatron, not anymore.
我们是斗不过威震天的！再也不能了
The war is over, and we lost.
战争结束了 我们一败涂地
You're giving up?!
你放弃了？
We can't just give up!
我们不能就这么放弃了！
Then tell me what we can do
那么你告诉我 我们还能做什么！
without communications, without a ground bridge,
没有了通信设备 没有了环陆桥
without a base of operations or resources of any kind!
没有了任何设备或物资…
Bee's right.
小蜂说得对
We know Starscream had access to a ground bridge while he was operating solo.
我们知道红蜘蛛在其单独行动期间 使用过环陆桥
Yes, yes, he'd clearly been using the derelict Decepticon ship the Harbinger.
是的 是的 他利用了霸天虎的废弃飞船 先驱号
What does that have to do with anything?!
但是那有什么用！
It could be full of Cybertronian tech,
那上面可能装满了各种塞博特恩资源
and it's probably abandoned again now
既然红蜘蛛已经回到虎子中间了
that Starscream's back with the 'Cons.
那飞船可能再次被遗弃了
Well, resources won't be of much use, not without someone to... lead us.
好吧 物资再多又能怎么样 如果没有人来…领导我们
It's a start!
但这是一个好的开始！
You'll have to start without me.
那你们去找别人一起开始吧！
This is someone else's fight now.
这场战争已经和我无关了
There is no one else, Ratchet... just us,
没有别人了 救护车 只有我们！
just the team.
只有领袖卫队！
Please!
拜托你们…
Just let me... rust in peace.
就让我安静地去自生自灭吧
Come on, Bee.
我们走吧 小蜂…
I'm back.
我回来了
I combed through every square micron of our old base.
我扫描了基地的每个角落
I couldn't find Ratchet's medical kit, not even a bandage.
也没能找到救护车的医药箱 甚至连条绷带都没有
The Forge... of Solus Prime.
卓天越…之锤…
It's gone, too. The 'Cons picked the place clean.
也没了 虎子们把基地搜刮得一干二净！
Wait,
等等
if you had the Forge, you could fix yourself up... power of the Primes.
如果你有了卓天越之锤 就能自我修复了 借领袖之力！
Optimus, hang on just a little longer.
擎天柱 再坚持一下
That hammer's got to be somewhere in Megatron's fortress.
锤子一定就在威震天堡垒的某个地方
Miko, wake up.
神子？快醒醒！
Why?
为什么？
Someone's coming.
有人来了
I'd know the hum of that engine anywhere!
不管在哪里 我都听得出这引擎声！
Ah! Jackie!
哈哈 老千！
Where have you been, buddy?!
你去哪儿啦 兄弟？
Catching up with a few old dance partners.
和几个老相识叙了叙旧
Good to see you, kid.
见到你很高兴 孩子
Safe to assume we're the only three Wreckers around?
看来这附近就只有我们三位雷霆救援队员了
So, what are we waiting for? Let's do some damage!
那我们还等什么？去闹个天翻地覆吧！
What's our next move, Jackie... circle back to base?
下一步做什么 老千？绕回基地？
There is no base. 'Cons blasted it to dust.
没有基地了 虎子们把那儿炸平了
The dimwit played right into my hands.
这些白痴果然被我玩弄于股掌之中…
All seekers to the flight deck! We have pinpointed the enemy!
集合全体追踪者 我们已锁定敌军位置！
Attack! My armada.
进攻 我的大军！
We're at the coordinates, Commander Starscream.
我们已到达指定坐标 红蜘蛛指挥官
Hold fast. They are approaching your position.
做好准备 他们正在向你们靠近…
Targets in range?
目标进入范围
And boom.
那就“轰”！
Grenade!
是手雷！
He... he tricked us!
他…他耍了我们？！
How'd you know the 'Cons planted a tracker on you?
你怎么知道虎子在你身上装了追踪器？
I figured the 'Cons were up to something,
我猜到虎子们会耍花招
so I did a little poking around under my hood.
于是我对引擎盖下面做了点儿小检查
Ha! That's my Jackie.
哈哈 不愧是我的老千
So, what's our next move?
那么 我们的下一步行动是什么？
I salvaged some munitions from the Jackhammer on my way out.
途中我从钻击号那里抢回了些弹药
You thought that made a loud noise?
你觉得刚才动静儿大吗？
Just wait.
好戏才刚开始…
Hold it right there, Bee.
就这样别动 小蜂
And... powering up!
然后 启动电源！
Keep trying. We'll figure it out.
再试试 我们会弄明白的！
Ah-ah-ah.
不对 不对 不对
You're miscalibrating the Energon transducer.
你们把能量转换装置都调校错了
Ratchet!
救护车！
Now step out of my way so I can work.
好啦 让开点儿 好让我工作！
The last time things looked this bleak, Optimus slipped me that key card...
上次事情变糟的时候 擎天柱给了我钥匙芯片！
something we could hang our hopes on.
至少我们还能把它当做希望！
I know you're feeling helpless, Jack.
我理解你无助的感觉 杰克
This doesn't need to be your burden.
但你不必把它当做负担
Stay behind me.
呆在我身后
Jack, I don't think we're gonna need that key card.
杰克 我觉得这次我们不需要钥匙芯片了
Meet Ultra Magnus.
来见见通天晓
So, not only did you fail to destroy the Autobots
你不仅没能消灭汽车人
but you allowed their number to increase!
还壮大了他们的队伍！
Is there no one who can bring me their heads?!
难道就没人能取得了汽车人的脑袋吗？
If I may, lord Megatron.
请允许我向您禀报 威震天陛下
During my exile on Cybertron,
我在塞博特恩的流亡期间
I resumed work on a long-dormant project...
我重新启动了一个搁置已久的研究项目
One that I believe may provide a solution to our current problem.
我相信这个项目能解决我们目前的难题
Cyber nucleic acid?
塞博特恩核酸？（类似人类的D.N.A.）
The building blocks of all Cybertronian life.
这是构建所有塞博特恩生命的基础
This hails from a specimen I excavated upon our planet
它源自我在塞星上发掘出的一个标本
and has yielded promising results.
而且对其检测的结果很令人满意
The Autobots continue to evade us.
汽车人屡次从我们手中逃脱
What makes you think we can afford to wait for the answer to our prayers to be
我们怎么能指望培养皿里产生的
birthed in some Petri dish?
…某种试验品呢？
You misunderstand.
你误解了我的意思
The subject has been fully cultivated.
实验对象已经被完全培育成功
It need only be transported from my laboratory on Cybertron.
我只需将其从塞博特恩的实验室传送过来
Then by all means, activate the space bridge.
那还等什么 启动太空桥！
I present to you, my liege...
很荣幸向您展示 我的君王
the ultimate Autobot hunter.
终极汽车人猎手！